all right the nifty is up about 50
points
banks are trying to make a bit of a
comeback the bank nifty is up about
three quarters of a percent
uh at 22 261.
sbi is flat icsa bank is up over one
percent
and you know we've got other names also
just barely coming back
uh into the green many of those names so
let's watch this space closely
uh you know in the financial space
there's news flow as well the government
has exempted icsc bank from reducing its
stakes in its insurance both life and
general insurance subsidies
to 30 which is the requirement but the
exemption has been given to icsa bank
to do this for a period of three years
my colleague yash is joining in
with the details on the story
well prashanth absolutely this would be
taken as a positive
for icici bank by the street and that
can be reflected in the stock price as
well today
what has happened is that the government
has exempted icici bank
from the restriction which bars banks
from holding over 30
stake in their subsidiaries in the case
of icici bank both life and general
insurance subsidiaries that is icsa true
life
and icici lombard now this exemption has
come under the section 192 of the
banking regulations act
and would be applicable for the next
three years uh from the date of
notification now what is uh
section 192 of the banking regulations
act essentially that section says that
no bank shall hold over 30
stake in any company whether as a
pledgey whether as a mortgage or an
absolute
owner now what is the current status as
far as icsa bank is concerned the icici
lombard the general insurance subsidy
has proposed a merger with bharti extra
general insurance and after that
the stake will come down to about 50 as
far as icsa potential is concerned icsa
bank stake there
is about fifty one point three seven
percent so of course uh
as per this regulation there was there
would have been a requirement of
diluting further twenty percent
but now the bank will have for the levy
for another three years
where it can look for the right
opportunities uh as far as offloading
that stake is concerned and not
rush into it simply because of the
timeline all right uh thank you yash for
giving us that story and all the details
over there with that we are completely
out of time on this edition of trading
hours so it's gonna be a wrap
from prashanth me and the entire team
but do keep it with us all the market
action the analysis continues
we have half time report coming up after
the break